Ariel Galvez

Software Engineer

Cochabamba, Bolivia (GTM -4)
(+591) 76918956
arielgp.70@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-g%C3%A1lvez-3b5119260
https://github.com/ArielGalvez

Full stack Engineer with 3 years of experience developing commercial software for international clients. Mainly used Typescript, React, Nestjs.

Attentive to quality of work in every stage of the development lifecycle from design, coding, debugging, testing, and maintenance.

Strong knowledge of HTML+CSS and ability to implement any complex design taking care of the responsive design.

Looking for a full stack or frontend position.

Bachelor's degree in computer science (System Engineering).

EXPERIENCE

Jalasoft, Software Engineer | Full stack developer

Opshero – November, 2021 – June, 2023

- Boosted application performance significantly by implementing caching and optimization techniques to reduce the network latency, minimize database queries, and improve the data access speeds.
 Decreased the system responsiveness to 40%.
- Developed and maintained internal tool boilerplate generator, which increase the efficiency for the
 development team. It helped to automate repetitive task, reduce errors, and ensure consistency
 across micro services projects. This result in a significant reduction in development time and improve
 the overall quality of the code base.
- Implemented responsive and user-friendly interfaces using Chakra ui and redux toolkit working closely with product managers and UX designers.
- Build and consumed RESTful APIs using Nestjs and Axios, to provide easier integration. I worked
 closely with other frontend developers, to understand their requirements and provide the necessary
 endpoints.
- Acted as a mentor and trained 3 new team members, providing guidance and support integrating them into technology, product knowledge, and development processes. Utilizing effective communication, I facilitated a smooth onboarding process, ensuring that new team members has the necessary resources and information to ramp up quickly.
- Implemented a feature allowing users to download a PDF, I used puppeteer to build PDF, I created template for the PDF invoices, incorporating branding elements and relevant information such as line items details, customer information and payment information. I ensured better user experience by providing a single click when downloading or visualizing using a custom component.

Tech Stack: Reactjs, Nestjs microservices, Bulljs, Redis, Docker, Chakra-ui, Sendgrid, Redux toolkit, Git, Github, Jira, Scrum, Kanban.

Ariel Galvez

Software Engineer

Cochabamba, Bolivia (GTM -4) (+591) 76918956

<u>arielgp.70@gmail.com</u>

<u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-g%C3%A1lvez-3b5119260</u>

<u>https://github.com/ArielGalvez</u>

- Development performing query response times, customizations, and enhancements as well as troubleshooting complex areas of major modules in the application.
- Implement Google and Facebook authentication.
- Backend development using C# with MongoDriver to connect database and FluentValidation to validate models.
- Frontend development with React, Typescript, Material-UI, and validations with Formik to build dynamic forms.
- Redesign and implementation of UX/UI application
- Backend Creation of Graphql Queries and Mutations to connect Services layer.
- Frontend State management with Redux Toolkit.
- Trained 13 new team members, integrated them into technology, product knowledge, and product processes.
- Strictly adhered to coding standards and coding practice and took care to uphold the Onion architect as defined in the project.
- Occasionally shared the knowledge to express ideas in order to increase code quality.

Tech Stack: Net Core, XUnit, Material-UI, MongoDB.Driver, FluentValidation, React, GraphQL, ReduxToolkit, Formik, Jest, Cloudinary CDN, GoogleAuth, Git, Gitlab, Trello.

Jalasoft Internship – Jan, 2020 – February, 2021

 IoT application to manage screens ads, using JavaScript frameworks and HTML5. Backend development with NodeJS, ExpressJS, mongoose while frontend for MVCs framework such as AngularJS. Creation of components.

Tech Stack: Angularjs, Express, Nodejs, Material ui, Git, Gitlab, Jira, RasberryPi3, RasberryPi4, Linux Ubuntu.

Jala Foundation, Software Engineer Trainee – Nov, 2018 – December, 2019

- I gained hands-on experience in web development using the MERN stack. This comprehensive technology stack includes MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js, and allows for efficient and scalable full-stack web development.
- During my training, I successfully developed two applications using the MERN stack, demonstrating my
 proficiency in this technology. These applications showcase my ability to design and develop webbased solutions that are both user-friendly and efficient.
- Through my work at Jala Foundation, I gained valuable experience collaborating with cross-functional teams and contributing to project success.

Ariel Galvez

Software Engineer

(+591) 76918956
arielgp.70@gmail.com
https://github.com/ArielGalvez

Cochabamba, Bolivia (GTM -4)

Tech Stack: MongoDB, Express, Reactjs, Nodejs.

PROJECTS

Poker Scrum – June, 2020 – August, 2020

- Webapp to help people to make easier and fun their estimations, works in real-time.
- I started the project as a joke, just to learn Graphql and improve Sass knowledge. After I realizing the
 powerups of Graphql Subscriptions, it ends up in something useful. Currently it is still using by my old
 team.

Weather App – September, 2020 – October, 2020

 During my free time, I challenged myself to create a React weather application as a personal project to learn Typescript. Through this project, I gained valuable experience in Typescript and honed my skills in React development.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Typescript, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Intermediate: C#, Basic: C++, Javas

Framework Tools: <u>Advanced</u>: Reactjs, Redux toolkit <u>Intermediate</u>: Nestjs, Nextjs, Express, Graphql, <u>Basic</u>: .Net Core.

Data Base: Advanced: PostgreSQL, Intermediate: MongoDB, Basic: SQL Server, MySQL.

Tools: VsCode, PgAdmin, Insomnia, Docker, Google Chrome, React Dev tools, Github, Github Actions. Google Cloud Platform.

Agile: Jira, Scrum, Kanban.

Languages: Upper Intermediate: English, Native: Spanish

EDUCATION

Universidad Mayor de San Simón – Cochabamba, Bolivia. Bachelor of Science in Systems Engineering, October 2018

- During my studies, I gained a strong foundation in object-oriented programming (OOP) and developed a solid understanding of HTML5, CSS3, and PHP.
- Through practical experience and coursework, I honed my skills in Java programming, using Java Swing and JavaFX to create a variety of projects. Many of these projects are available on my public Github account, showcasing my proficiency in Java development.